<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docs on Systems Theory for Institutional Research (STIR)</title>
    <link>https://syres.org/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docs on Systems Theory for Institutional Research (STIR)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://syres.org/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developing Meaningful Analytics Dashboards in Higher Education: Institutional Research as a Bridge Between ‘Signal’ and ‘Meaning’</title>
      <link>https://syres.org/docs/proposal1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://syres.org/docs/proposal1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-proposal&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Research Proposal&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#research-proposal&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;developing-meaningful-analytics-dashboards-in-higher-education-institutional-research-as-a-bridge-between-signal-and-meaning&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Developing Meaningful Analytics Dashboards in Higher Education: Institutional Research as a Bridge Between ‘Signal’ and ‘Meaning’&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#developing-meaningful-analytics-dashboards-in-higher-education-institutional-research-as-a-bridge-between-signal-and-meaning&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Abstract&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In today’s data-rich higher education environment, translating raw signals (data) into meaningful insights is critical for strategic decision-making. This research explores how Institutional Research (IR) can facilitate the development of an effective analytics dashboard aligned with a Dean’s Key Performance Areas (KPAs) and Key Performance Indicators (KPIs). Drawing on Niklas Luhmann’s theoretical concepts of &lt;em&gt;“Meaning”&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;“Signal,”&lt;/em&gt; the proposal argues that IR plays a central mediating role, turning raw data into actionable information by embedding it within the dean’s strategic context. Through a conceptual and document-based analysis, this study outlines how IR practitioners can collaborate with technical teams (developers, data engineers) and academic leaders to ensure dashboards are both methodologically sound and contextually relevant. An in-depth chapter delves into Luhmann’s understanding of &lt;em&gt;“Signal”&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;“Meaning,”&lt;/em&gt; clarifying why his framework provides a powerful rationale for designing higher education analytics. Ultimately, this proposal demonstrates how carefully crafted dashboards can bridge disparate stakeholder priorities, leading to more robust and meaningful decision-making processes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
